Granville Hicks Papers
Granville Hicks Papers
1906-1980
Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982
75 linear ft.
Papers of the American author, lecturer, novelist, and literary critic. Correspondence, 1929-80, with Harriette Arnow, Newton Arvin, Van Wyck Brooks, Baker Bromell, Malcolm Cowley, Robert Cantwell, Robert Gorham Davis, Henry Christman, George Cole, James T. Farrell, Joseph Freeman, Herbert Gold, Corliss Lamont, Lucy Robbins Lang, John Lydenburg, Georgia McKinley, Fulmer Mood, Walter Ripton Morris, Wright Morris, Richard Rovere, Evelyn Scott, Lincoln Steffins, and Ella Winter, among others. Also correspondence and editorial reader's reports for Macmillan Publishing Company. Writings include articles, book manuscripts, a journal (1942-1973), lectures, as well as research notes, correspondence, and memorabilia relating to the production of Hicks' biography of John Reed. Large collection of printed material includes book reviews, clippings, and an assortment of Leftist pamphlets and periodicals from the 1930s.
149049
Biographical History
Granville Hicks (1901-1982) was an American Marxist and later anti-Marxist novelist, literary critic, educator, and editor.
Born September 9, 1901, in Exeter, NH, to Frank Stevens and Carrie Weston (Horne) Hicks, Granville Hicks earned his bachelor's degree at Harvard University in 1923, and a Master's in 1929. He also studied for two years at Harvard Theological School. In 1925 he married Dorothy Dyer, with whom he had a daughter, Stephanie.
From 1925-1928 Hicks taught at Smith College in Northampton, MA as an instructor in biblical literature. He was an assistant professor of English at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute (1929-35) and a counselor in American civilization at Harvard (1938-39). For three years (1955-1958) he taught novel writing at the New School for Social Research in New York. He was a visiting professor at New York University (1959), Syracuse University (1960), and Ohio University (1967-68). He was the director of the Yaddo artists' community beginning in 1942 and later served as its acting executive director. For 35 years (1930-1965) he was the literary advisor to Macmillan Publishers.
Hicks was a highly influential Marxist literary critic during the 1930s, well-known for his involvement in a number of celebrated causes (including his well-publicized resignation from the Communist Party in 1939). He established his reputation as an important literary critic with the 1933 publication of The Great Tradition: An Interpretation of American Literature since the Civil War, a systematic history of American literature from a Marxist perspective. In 1932 he voted for the Communist Party ticket and joined almost all the significant Communist party front groups of the 1930s. In 1934 Hicks joined the Communist Party itself and became editor of its cultural magazine The New Masses.
In 1935 Hicks was let go from his teaching position at Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute, a dismissal he claimed was politically motivated although school officials denied this. He continued to teach at various institutions but devoted more and more of his time to writing. In 1936 Hicks was asked to co-write John Reed: The Making of a Revolutionary, a biography of the radical journalist and author of Ten Days that Shook the World. Communist Party chairman Earl Browder pressured Hicks to remove several passages that reflected negatively on the Soviet Union, but in the end the book was praised for its even-handed and unbiased presentation.
In 1939, in protest against the Nazi-Soviet non-aggression pact, Hicks resigned from the Communist Party. He attempted to organize an independent left-wing alternative organization, but with little success. By 1940 he had entirely renounced Communism and termed himself a democratic socialist; that same year he wrote an essay for The Nation entitled, "The Blind Alley of Marxism." During the 1950s Hicks testified before the House Un-American Activities Committee twice, and in 1954 in his essay titled "The Liberals Who Haven't Learned," he "unambiguously characterized the aim of communism as 'brutal revolutionary totalitarianism,' and chided liberals for providing a 'verbal cloak of "social betterment"' for the Soviets."
Hicks died June 18, 1982, in Franklin Park, NJ. By the time of his death, his early radical/Marxist writings were balanced by his later turn to a broader, more humanistic criticism.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Granville Hicks Papers consist of correspondence - subject files, writings, memorabilia, printed material, galleys, proofs and review copies, manuscripts and published material about the American writer, lecturer, literary critic, educator, and editor. Correspondence-subject files includes family (primarily wife Dorothy) and Hicks' agent agent Henry Volkening, as well as authors (Newton Arvin, Saul Bellow, Erskine Caldwell, Willa Cather, James Fenimore Cooper, James Gould Cozzens, William Faulkner, Henry James, Lucy Robins Lang, Samuel Levenson, John Lydenburg, Wright Morris, Braham Norwick, Joyce Carol Oates, Flannery O'Connor, David Graham Phillips, Richard Rovere, J. D. Salinger, Lincoln Steffens, Arnold J. Toynbee, Mark Twain, Ursula Genung Walker, Asa Wilgus, Edmund Wilson), poets (William Cullen Bryant, Corliss Lamont, Chard Powers Smith, Harvey Curtis Webster), publications (The Atlantic Monthly, Chicago Tribune, Daedalus, Harper's, Harvard Communist, Kenyon Review, Meanjin, Modern Socialism, New York Herald Tribune, Saturday Review), publishers (Doubleday, Dutton, Macmillan, Modern Age Books, Putnam, Viking Press), universities (Bennington College, Cornell University, Harvard University, the New School for Social Research, Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute), professional and other organizations (Famous Writers School, League of American Writers, Literary Guild of America, National Committee for the Defense of Political Prisoners, Rockefeller Foundation, Yaddo), and other American radicals (Earl Browder, Malcolm Cowley, James T. Farrell), as well as topics such as American literature, Fabian socialism, Grafton, New York (Hicks' home town), economic conditions in Great Britain and the United States, the Harvard-Sacco-Vanzetti Committee, the House Committee on Un-American Activities, Marxist study group, and Hicks' resignation from Communist Party. There are also folders devoted to Hicks' books including Small Town and The Great Tradition.
Writings comprises articles, books (both by and about Hicks, including extensive research files for John Reed: the Making of a Revolutionary), journals, lectures, and reader's reports. Memorabilia contains an assortment of material including address books, notes, college course material, and photographs. Printed material consists of book reviews of Hicks' work, clippings, pamphlets, periodicals (Communist Review, Harvard Monthly, Hound and Horn, The New Leader, Partisan Review, Science and Society: a Marxian Quarterly).
Drafts and other pre-publication material are located in Unrevised galleys, proofs and review copies, while material about Hicks comprises Manuscripts and published material about Granville Hicks. The final series, Miscellaneous material, includes among other things several articles by John Reed and a poster for the exhibit "Art for The Masses (1911-1917): a Radical Magazine and its Graphics."
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence-subject files is arranged alphabetically. Writings and Printed material are arranged alphabetically by type and then by title or topic. Memorabilia is arranged alphabetically by type. Galleys and Manuscripts are arranged alphabetically by author.
Separated Material
A number of the books and periodicals that originally came with the collection have been removed for separate cataloging. These items are noted in the inventory as "Transferred to Rare Books" and can be located using.
Subject and Genre Headings
Radicalism; Biography; Literature -- American Fiction; Abbe, George, 1911-1989.; Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951.; Algren, Nelson, 1909-1981.; Allen, Devere, 1891-1955.; Arnow, Harriette Louisa Simpson, 1908-1986.; Arvin, Newton, 1900-1963.; Bellow, Saul.; Bixler, Julius Seelye, 1894-1985.; Bliven, Bruce, 1889-1977.; Bourjaily, Vance, 1922-2010.; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.; Browder, Earl, 1891-1973.; Brownell, Baker, 1887-1965.; Bryant, Louise, 1885-1936.; Burroughs, Harry E. (Harry Ernest), 1890-; Calverton, vol. F. (Victor Francis), 1900-1940.; Cantwell, Robert, 1908-1978.; Cargill, Oscar, 1898-1972.; Carroll, Gladys Hasty, 1904-1999.; Cheever, John.; Chevalier, Haakon, 1902-1985.; Champney, Freeman.; Conroy, Jack, 1898-1990.; Corey, Lewis.; Cowley, Malcolm, 1898-1989.; Cruden, Robert.; Curti, Merle (Merle Eugene), 1897-1996.; Dahlberg, Edward, 1900-1977.; Davis, Robert Gorham.; Dell, Floyd, 1887-1969.; De Voto, Bernard, 1897-1955.; Doughty, Howard, 1904-; Draper, Theodore, 1912-2006.; Dupee, F. W. (Frederick Wilcox), 1904-1979.; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969.; Farrell, James T. (James Thomas), 1904-1979.; Frank, Waldo David, 1889-1967.; Freeman, Joseph, 1897-1965.; Fry, Varian, 1907-1967.; Gold, Herbert, 1924-; Gold, Michael, 1893-1967.; Goldman, Emma, 1869-1940.; Gregory, Horace, 1898-1982.; Hallowell, Robert.; Haydn, Hiram Collins, 1907-1973.; Herbst, Josephine, 1892-1969.; Hicks, Granville, 1901-1982.; Hillyer, Robert, 1895-1961.; Kennedy, William, 1928-; Kreymborg, Alfred, 1883-1966.; Krutch, Joseph Wood, 1893-1970.; Lamont, Corliss, 1902-1995.; Levenson, Sam, 1911-1980.; MacLeish, Archibald, 1892-1982.; Madden, David, 1933-; Matthiessen, F. O. (Francis Otto), 1902-1950.; Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis), 1880-1956.; Morris, Wright, 1910-1998.; Nevins, Allan, 1890-1971.; O'Connor, Flannery.; Painter, Charlotte.; Page, Myra, 1897-1993.; Owen, Guy, 1925-1981.; Parrington, Vernon Louis, 1871-1929.; Reed, John, 1887-1920.; Robbins, Jack Alan.; Roskolenko, Harry.; Rovere, Richard H. (Richard Halworth), 1915-1979.; Schorer, Mark, 1908-1977.; Scott, Evelyn, 1893-1963.; Simonson, Lee, 1888-1967.; Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968.; Smith, Chard Powers, 1894-1977.; Steffens, Lincoln, 1866-1936.; Wilson, Edmund, 1895-1972.; Winter, Ella.; Wolfe, Bertram D. (Bertram David), 1896-1977.; American Civil Liberties Union.; Macmillan Company.; New School for Social Research (New York, N.Y.: 1919-1997); Yaddo (Artists' colony); New leader (New York, N.Y.); New masses.; Saturday review.; American literature -- 20th century -- History and criticism.; Authors, American.; Biographers -- Authorship.; City and town life -- United States.; Communism -- United States.; Communism and education.; Communism and intellectuals.; Community life.; Critics -- United States; Literary historians.; Literary quarrels.; Literature -- History and criticism.; Marxist criticism.; Novelists, American.; Publishers and publishing.; Radicalism -- United States.; United States -- Intellectual life -- 20th century.; Articles.; Book reviews.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Drafts (documents); Diaries.; Lectures.; Manuscripts for publication.; Pamphlets.; Periodicals.; Biographers.; Critics.; Novelists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Majority gift of Granville Hicks. A few items, gift of others, as noted in the inventory below.
Inventory
- Correspondence - subject files
  - A (Box 1)
  - AAUW Schenectady course, "American Literature Since the War" (Box 1)
  - AAUW Schenectady course, creative writing (Box 1)
  - Aaron, Daniel (Box 1)
  - Abbe, George Bancroft (Box 1)
  - Abrams, Ray H. (Box 1)
  - Adamic, Louis (Box 1)
  - Adams, Florence, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Adams, Franklin Pierce (Box 1)
  - Adams, Henry Hitch (Box 1)
  - Adams, J. Donald (Box 1)
  - Adams, Pat (Box 1)
  - Adams, Samuel Hopkins (Box 1)
  - Addison-Wesley Publishing Company (Box 1)
  - Afro-American literature (Box 1)
  - Agan, Calvin E., 1862 - 1865; Civil War letters (Box 1)
  - Agan Family (Box 1)
  - Agee, James (Box 1)
  - Agronsky, Martin (Box 1)
  - Aiken, Conrad (Box 1)
  - Aladjem, Henrietta (Box 1)
  - Albany Public Library (Box 1)
  - Aldington, Richard (Box 1)
  - Aldridge, James (Box 1)
  - Aldridge, John W. (Box 1)
  - Aldwell, Thomas T. (Box 1)
  - Algren, Nelson (Box 1)
  - Allen, Arthur, 1938-1946; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Allen, Devere (Box 1)
  - Allen, Elizabeth (Box 1)
  - Allen, Frederick Lewis (Box 1)
  - Allen, Helena G. (Box 1)
  - Allen, Jerry (Box 1)
  - Allen, Patricia R. (Box 1)
  - Allin, J. Bryan (Box 1)
  - Allinson, Brent Dow (Box 1)
  - America Illustrated, See U.S. Information Agency.
  - American Author and Critics, series (Box 1)
  - American Broadcasting Company (Box 1)
  - American Cancer Society (Box 1)
    See also Writings: Miscellany: Unpublished: "Wedding Belles".
  - American Caravan (Box 1)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box 2)
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom (Box 2)
  - American Defense, Harvard Group (Box 2)
  - American Forum for Socialist Education (Box 2)
  - American Heritage Dictionary of the English Language (Box 2)
  - American Library Association (Box 2)
  - American literature, notes, outlines; 2 folders (Box 2)
  - American Mercury (Box 2)
  - American Review (Box 2)
  - The American Scholar (Box 2)
  - American Spectator (Box 2)
  - The American Teacher (Box 2)
  - American Way, 1974-1976; undated; drafts, articles, miscellany; 3 folders
  - American Writers Congress (Box 2)
  - "America's Town Meeting of the Air" (Box 2)
    See also Life.
  - Ames, Elizabeth, See Yaddo.
  - Amis, Lola Jones (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Courtney (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Sherwood (Box 2)
  - Anderson, Thomas (Box 2)
  - Angoff, Charles (Box 2)
    See also American Mercury.
  - Annunziata, Frank (Box 2)
  - Anonymous (Box 2)
  - Anspacher, Louis Kaufman (Box 2)
  - Anthropology (Box 2)
  - Antioch College (Box 2)
  - Antioch Review (Box 2)
  - Appel, Benjamin (Box 2)
  - Appleton-Century-Crofts, Inc. (Box 2)
  - Arents (George) Research Library, See Syracuse University Library. (Box 2)
  - Arno Press (Box 2)
  - Arnold, Elliott (Box 2)
  - Arnold, Joan (Box 2)
  - Arnow, Harriette Louisa (Simpson), 1946-1954; undated; 6 folders (Box 3)
  - Arvin, Neil Cole (Box 3)
  - Arvin, Newton, 1929-1943; 11 folders (Box 3)
  - Arvin, Newton, 1944-1963; undated; 19 folders (Box 4)
  - Arvin, Newton, 3 folders (Box 5)
  - Arvin, Robert H. (Box 5)
  - Ashman, Richard (Box 5)
  - Aswell, Edward C. (Box 5)
  - Atheneum Publishers (Box 5)
  - Atherton, Gertrude (Box 5)
  - Atkinson, Brooks (Box 5)
  - The Atlantic Monthly (Box 5)
  - Atlantic Monthly Press (Box 5)
  - Atlas, James (Box 5)
  - Auchincloss, Louis (Box 5)
  - Auden, Wystan Hugh (Box 5)
  - Auerback, Erich - Mimesis (Box 5)
  - Authors' League of America, Inc. (Box 5)
  - Ayres, Clarence Edwin (Box 5)
  - BA - BON (Box 5)
  - BOO - BZ (Box 5)
  - Babcock, Clarence Merton (Box 5)
  - Bahr, Jerome (Box 5)
  - Bailie, Helen Tufts (Box 5)
  - Baird, Martha (Box 5)
  - Baker, Bliss Y. (Box 5)
  - Baker, Carlos (Box 5)
  - Baker, Ray Palmer (Box 5)
  - Balch, Marston (Box 5)
  - Baldwin, James (Box 5)
  - Baldwin, Roger Nash (Box 5)
  - Balivet, Henry P. (Box 5)
  - Ballantine Books, Inc. (Box 5)
  - Bandler, Bernard (Box 5)
  - Bardin, John Franklin (Box 5)
  - Barnes, Djuna (Box 5)
  - Barnes, Eric Wollencott (and Peggy) (Box 5)
  - Barnes, Harry Elmer (Box 5)
  - Barres, Maurice (Box 5)
  - Barrie, John T. (Box 5)
  - Barron's Educational Series (Box 6)
  - Barth, John (Box 6)
  - Barth, Lawrence (Box 6)
  - Bartley, William Warren (Box 6)
  - Barzun, Jacques (Box 6)
  - Bates, Ralph (Box 6)
  - Baugh, Hansell (Box 6)
  - Baxandall, Lee (Box 6)
  - Beacon Press (Box 6)
  - Beard, Mary Ritter (Box 6)
  - Beardsley, Aubrey (Box 6)
  - Beatty, Bessie (Box 6)
  - Becker, Maurice (Box 6)
  - Beekman, E.M. (Box 6)
  - Beffel, John Nicholas (Box 6)
  - Behnke, John Alden (Box 6)
  - Behold Trouble (Box 6)
  - Bein, Albert (Box 6)
  - Belitt, Ben (Box 6)
  - Bell, Daniel (Box 6)
  - Bellamy, Edward (Box 6)
  - Bellow, Saul, 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Benchly, Alexandra Jane (Box 6)
  - Bendiner, Robert (Box 6)
  - Bennett, Arnold (Box 6)
  - Bennett, Richard, 1936-1973; undated; 2 folders (Box 6)
  - Bennington College (Box 6)
  - Bensman, Joseph (Box 6)
  - Bercovici, Konrad (Box 6)
  - Bercovici, Rion. "A Radical Childhood." Scribner's Magazine, 1932 (Box 6)
  - Beregoff-Gillow, Pauline (Box 6)
  - Bergamini, David (Box 6)
  - Berger, Arthur Asa (Box 6)
  - Berger, Thomas (Box 6)
  - Berkeley Publishing Corp. (Box 6)
  - Berkshires project, 5 folders (Box 6)
  - Berkshires project, 5 folders (Box 7)
  - Berlin Central School (Box 7)
  - Bernard, Jessie Shirley (Box 7)
  - Bessie, Alvah C. (Box 7)
  - Best, Herbert (Box 7)
  - Best, Marshall Ayers (Box 7)
  - Between Worlds (Box 7)
  - Bicker, Robert J. (Box 7)
  - Bickford, Mildred, 1935-1961; undated; 9 folders (Box 7)
  - Bickford, Mildred, undated; 4 folders (Box 8)
  - Biddle, George (Box 8)
  - Bierce, Ambrose (Box 8)
  - Binger, Carl Alfred Lanning (Box 8)
  - Bingham, Alfred Mitchell (Box 8)
  - Bingham, Edwin R. (Box 8)
  - Birdsall, Richard (Box 8)
  - Birk, Louis P. (Box 8)
    See also Modern Age Books.
  - Birk, Newman Peter (Box 8)
  - Birkbeck, Barbara, See Grever, Barbara Ann.
  - Bisbee, Eleanor (Box 8)
  - Bitker, Marjorie M. (Box 8)
  - Bixler, Julius Seelye (Box 8)
  - Bixler, Paul Howard (Box 8)
  - Blackmur, Richard P. (Box 8)
  - Blackwell, Louise (Box 8)
  - Blair and Ketchum's Country Journal (Box 8)
  - Blake, Ben (Box 8)
  - Blankfort, Michael (Box 8)
  - Blankman, Edward (Box 8)
  - Blaustein, J.M. (Box 8)
  - Bliven, Bruce (Box 8)
  - Bloom, Edward Alan (Box 8)
  - Blotner, Joseph L. The Political Novel, 1955 (Box 8)
  - Bluefarb, Sam (Box 8)
  - Blythe, Samuel George (Box 8)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company, Inc. (Box 8)
  - Bode, Elroy (Box 8)
  - Bodley, Nicholas B. "The Auloi of Meroe", 1946 (Box 8)
  - Bohn, Frank (Box 8)
  - Bohn, William Edward (Box 8)
  - Boles, Paul Darcy (Box 8)
  - Bond, Julian (Box 8)
  - Bonner, Amy (Box 8)
  - Bonnes, Eleanor, See Webb, Eleanor.
  - Book-of-the-Month Club, Inc. (Box 8)
  - Book Union, Inc. (Box 8)
  - Book Week, See New York Herald Tribune.
  - The Bookman (Box 9)
  - Books Abroad (Box 9)
  - Boorstin, Daniel (Box 9)
  - Booth, Wayne C. (Box 9)
  - Born, Edith de (Box 9)
  - Boston Herald (Box 9)
  - Boston Traveler (Box 9)
  - Boston University (Box 9)
  - Botkin, Ben A. (Box 9)
  - Boudin, Louis B. (Box 9)
  - Bourjaily, Vance (Box 9)
  - Bouscaren, Anthony Trawick (Box 9)
  - Bowen, Joan (Mrs. Ezra), See Williams, Joan.
  - Bowen, Stirling (Box 9)
  - Bower, Warren (Box 9)
  - Bowman, John Scott (Box 9)
  - Bowman, Sylvia E. (Box 9)
  - Boyce, Burke (Box 9)
  - Boyd, Ernest, "Marxian Literary Critics" Scribner's Magazine (Box 9)
  - Boyd, Fred Sumner (Box 9)
  - Boyd, Jack Kent (Box 9)
  - Boyd, Thomas Alexander (Box 9)
  - Boyden, Polly Chase (Box 9)
  - Boyesen, Hjalmar Hjorst (Box 9)
  - Brace, Ernest (Box 9)
  - Bradbury, John M. (Box 9)
  - Bragin, Moe (Box 9)
  - Braine, John (Box 9)
  - Branch, Edgar Marquess (Box 9)
  - Bransten, Richard (Box 9)
  - Braude, Jacob Morton (Box 9)
  - George Braziller, Inc. (Box 9)
  - Bread Loaf Writers' Conference (Box 9)
  - Brennan, Frederick Hazlitt (Box 9)
  - Bridgman, Walter Ray (Box 9)
  - Brinckle, Gertrude (Box 9)
  - Brinton, Crane (Box 9)
  - Brittain, Joan T. "Symbols of Violence: Flannery O'Connor's Structure of Reality", thesis (Box 9)
  - Brittain, Joan T. (Box 9)
    See also Driskell, Leon vol..
  - Brody, Catharine (Box 9)
  - Brokaw, Warren Edwin (Box 9)
  - Bromer, Richard (Box 9)
  - Bromfield, Louis (Box 9)
  - Brook, Ethel Saniel (Box 9)
  - Brooks, Cleanth (Box 9)
  - Brooks, John Nixon (Box 9)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck (Box 9)
  - Broun, Heywood (Box 9)
  - Browder, Earl, 2 folders (Box 9)
  - Brown, Alice (Box 9)
  - Brown, Harry Peter (Box 9)
  - Brown, Robert Bruce (Box 9)
  - Brown, Robert C. (Box 9)
  - Brown, Robert Carlton (Box 9)
  - Brown, Slater (Box 9)
  - Brown, Stuart Gerry (Box 9)
  - Brown, Susan Jenkins (Box 9)
  - Brownell, Baker, 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Brownson, Orestes Augustus (Box 10)
  - Brubaker, Howard (Box 10)
  - Bruccoli, Matthew Joseph (Box 10)
  - Bruce, Jeannette (Box 10)
  - Bryant, Jerry H. (Box 10)
  - Bryant, Margaret M. (Box 10)
  - Bryant, William Cullen (Box 10)
  - Bubka, Tony (Box 10)
  - Buck, Paul (Box 10)
  - Buck, Pearl S. (Box 10)
  - Bufkin, E.C. (Box 10)
  - Bulgheroni, Marisa (Box 10)
  - Bulletin correspondence, 1940; undated; 4 folders (Box 10)
  - Bullitt, William C. (Box 10)
  - Bumbalo, Victor (Box 10)
  - Bunce, Stan (Box 10)
  - Burgess, Anthony (Box 10)
  - Burgess, Jackson (Box 10)
  - Burgum, Edwin Berry (Box 10)
  - Burke, Fielding (Box 10)
  - Burke, Kenneth (Box 10)
  - Burleson, Christine (Box 10)
  - Burnett, Whit (Box 10)
  - Burns, Wayne (Box 11)
  - Burnshaw, Stanley (Box 11)
  - Burroughs, Harry E. (Box 11)
  - Burwick, Frederick (Box 11)
  - Business Week (Box 11)
  - Butler, Arthur Pierce (Box 11)
  - Butler, Samuel (Box 11)
  - Buttitta, Anthony (Box 11)
  - Button, Daniel E. (Box 11)
  - Byrne, Robert (Box 11)
  - C (Box 11)
  - CBS News (Box 11)
  - Cabell, James Branch (Box 11)
  - Cable, George W. (Box 11)
  - Cadbury, Henry Joel (Box 11)
  - Cady, Howard S. (Box 11)
    See also Macmillan Company.
  - Cain, James M. (Box 11)
  - Caldwell, Erskine (Box 11)
  - Caldwell, Taylor (Box 11)
  - Call Association, Inc. (Box 11)
  - Callaghan, Morley (Box 11)
  - Callender, Wesley P. (Box 11)
  - Calmer, Alan (Box 11)
  - Calvert, Bruce T. (Box 11)
  - Calverton, Victor Francis, 2 folders (Box 11)
  - Cambridge University Press (Box 11)
  - "Camera Three" (Box 11)
  - Cameron, Leslie G. (Box 11)
  - Campbell, Bhain, See Campbell, Robert Bhain.
  - Campbell, Robert Bhain (Box 11)
  - Canfield, Cass (Box 11)
  - Canfield, Dorothy, See Fisher, Dorothy Canfield.
  - Cantor, Arthur (Box 11)
  - Cantril, Hadley (Box 11)
  - Cantwell, Robert (Box 11)
  - Capote, Truman (Box 11)
  - Capouya, Emile (Box 12)
  - Cappers, Elmer Osgood (Box 12)
  - Cappon, Alexander (Box 12)
  - Carb, David (Box 12)
  - CARE, Inc. (Box 12)
  - Carew, Kate (Box 12)
  - Cargill, Oscar (Box 12)
  - Carlyle, Thomas (Box 12)
  - Carmer, Carl Lamson (Box 12)
  - Carmon, Walt, See International Literature.
  - Carpenter, Frederic Ives (Box 12)
  - Carpenter, Margaret (Box 12)
  - Carpenter, Niles (Box 12)
  - Carroll, Gladys Hasty (Box 12)
  - Carter, Harvey (Box 12)
  - Carter, Paul Allen (Box 12)
  - Cary, Joyce (Box 12)
  - Casanova, Grace Hegger (Box 12)
  - Caspary, Vera (Box 12)
  - Cassel, E.E. (Box 12)
  - Cather, Willa (Box 12)
  - Cawelti, John G. (Box 12)
  - Caylor, George N. (Box 12)
  - The Centennial Review (Box 12)
  - Century Company (Box 12)
  - Cerf, Bennett (Box 12)
  - Chamberlain, John (Box 12)
  - Chamberlin, William Henry (Box 12)
  - Chambers, Mary (Mrs. Kellett), See Carew, Kate.
  - Chambers, Whittaker (Box 12)
  - Champney, Freeman (Box 12)
  - Chang, Diana (Box 12)
  - Channing, William Ellery (Box 12)
  - Chase, Edward Everett (Box 12)
  - Chase, Edward T. (Box 12)
  - Chase, Mary Ellen (Box 12)
  - Chase, Stuart (Box 12)
  - Chasse, Robert (Box 12)
  - Chatham College (Box 12)
  - Chatham College course: "American Fiction Writers Since 1945" (Box 12)
  - Chatham College course: "Major American Writers 1855-1945" (Box 12)
  - Chatham College course: "Politics and Literature in the 1930's" (Box 12)
  - Cheever, John (Box 12)
  - Chen, Han-sheng (Box 12)
  - Chertok, Sidney L. (Box 12)
  - Cheslaw, Irving (Box 12)
  - Chevalier, Haakon (Box 12)
  - Chicago, University of (Box 12)
  - University of Chicago Press (Box 12)
  - Chicago Sun-Times (Box 12)